window.quizData = [
  {
    question:
      "Indian classical dance techniques like Rasa and Bhava trace their origins to —",
    options: [
      "Abhinaya Darpana",
      "Bharatmuni's Natyashastra",
      "Sangeet Ratnakar",
      "Natya Veda",
    ],
    answer: "Bharatmuni's Natyashastra",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Lavani, Powada, Koli, Waghya Murali and Dhangari Gaja are folk dances from —",
    options: ["Gujarat", "Maharashtra", "Karnataka", "Madhya Pradesh"],
    answer: "Maharashtra",
  },

  {
    question: "The one-act play of Sattriya is called —",
    options: ["Yakshagana", "Ankiya Nat", "Therukoothu", "Jatra"],
    answer: "Ankiya Nat",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The origin of most of the classical dance forms of India is from —",
    options: [
      "Natya Shastra",
      "Rig Veda",
      "Silappadikaram",
      "Sangeet Ratnakar",
    ],
    answer: "Natya Shastra",
  },

  {
    question: "The dance form of Goa which is known as 'Warrior Dance' is —",
    options: ["Ghode Modni", "Dhalo", "Fugdi", "Dekhnni"],
    answer: "Ghode Modni",
  },

  {
    question: "Manipuri dance is based on Rasleela themes of —",
    options: [
      "Shiva and Parvati",
      "Radha and Krishna",
      "Rama and Sita",
      "Vishnu and Lakshmi",
    ],
    answer: "Radha and Krishna",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Sattriya (Assam) was recognised as a Classical dance by the Sangeet Natak Akademi in —",
    options: ["1998", "2000", "2002", "2004"],
    answer: "2000",
  },

  {
    question:
      "UNESCO recognized 'Mudiyettu,' a ritual-drama of Kerala, as an 'intangible cultural heritage of humanity' in —",
    options: ["2008", "2009", "2010", "2011"],
    answer: "2010",
  },

  {
    question: "Thullal dance originated from —",
    options: ["Tamil Nadu", "Kerala", "Andhra Pradesh", "Karnataka"],
    answer: "Kerala",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The 'Ka Shad Mastieh' or victory dance of the Khasi tribe is from —",
    options: ["Nagaland", "Assam", "Manipur", "Meghalaya"],
    answer: "Meghalaya",
  },
];
